Guide to the Aleksander Wat Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Writings of Others, 1921-1988; Series IV; 0.63; (2 boxes)
  - Witkiewicz, Stanisław Ignacy, "Aleksander Wat," typescript, 1921 (Box 40, Folder 872)
  - Wittlin, Joseph, "Literary Program," typescript (copy), 1963 (Box 40, Folder 873)
  - Wojdyło, Marek, "Malarstwo i kolor w poezji Aleksandra Wata," offprint, 1985-1986 (Box 40, Folder 874)
  - Zieliński, Jan, "Spowiedź syna królewskiego," typescript (copy), 1983 (Box 40, Folder 875)
  - Various authors, poems dedicated to Aleksander Wat, 1967, undated (Box 40, Folder 876-877)
  - Various authors, copies of articles on Aleksander Wat and related topics, 1958-1987 (Box 40, Folder 878-879)
  - Various authors, copies of articles on Aleksander Wat and related topics (continued), 1958-1987 (Box 41, Folder 880-886)
- Printed Material, 1920-1978; Series V; 1.25; (3 boxes)
  Series V is organized by type of material.
  Series V consists of newspaper clippings about topics related to Aleksander Wat (including Polish literature and history) and books of poetry and literature annotated by Wat.
  - Clippings from the foreign press (outside Poland), 1959-1977 (Box 42, Folder 887-888)
  - Clippings from the Polish émigré press, 1967-1978
  - Clippings from Wiadomości, 1958-1977 (Box 42, Folder 889-890)
  - Clippings from the Polish press, 1948-1968 (Box 42, Folder 891-903)
  - Clippings, writings of Aleksander Wat, 1948-1968 (Box 42, Folder 904-910)
  - Clippings, obituary and reminiscences, 1967 (Box 42, Folder 911)
  - Other clippings, 1967-1985 (Box 43, Folder 912-918)
    Includes writings of Paulina Wat.
  - Printed material annotated by Aleksander Wat and Paulina Wat, 1920-1977 (Box 43, Folder 919-923)
    Includes a 1920 edition of JA z jednej strony i JA z drugiej strony mego mopsożelaznego piecyka, signed and annotated by Aleksander Wat.
    Includes a 1920 edition of Gga, pierwszy polski almanach futurystyczny, signed by Anatol Stern and Aleksander Wat.
  - Printed material annotated by Aleksander Wat and Paulina Wat, 1950-1982, undated (Box 44, Folder 924-932)
  - Printed material annotated by Aleksander Wat and Paulina Wat (copies), undated (Box 45, Folder 933-934)
- Oversize Papers
  - Ciemne świecidło, title page, proof (Series II), 1968 (Box 46, Folder 935)
  - Mój Wiek, Clippings, reviews and other related printed material (Series II), 1970s (Box 46, Folder 936)
  - Ucieczka Lotha, printed excerpts (Series II), 1949, 1967 (Box 46, Folder 937)
  - Biographical information about Aleksander Wat, clippings (Series II), undated (Box 46, Folder 938)
  - Documents (Poland) (Series III), 1919 (Box 46, Folder 939)
  - Medical papers (Series III), 1959 (Box 46, Folder 940)
  - Iwaniuk, Wacław, poems dedicated to Paulina Wat, printed version (Series IV), 1978 (Box 46, Folder 941)
  - Clippings from the foreign press (outside Poland) (SeriesV), 1959-1977 (Box 46, Folder 942-943)
  - Clippings from the Polish émigré press (Series V), 1967-1978 (Box 46, Folder 944)
  - Clippings from Wiadomości (Series V), 1958-1977 (Box 46, Folder 945-946)
  - Clippings from the Polish press (Series V), 1948-1968 (Box 46, Folder 947-948)
  - Clippings, writings of Aleksander Wat (Series V), 1948-1968 (Box 46, Folder 949)
  - Clippings, obituary and reminiscences (Series V), 1967 (Box 46, Folder 950)
  - Other clippings (Series V), 1967-1985 (Box 46, Folder 951)
  - Printed material, Gga, pierwszy polski almanach futurystyczny, 1920 (Box 46, Folder 952)
- Restricted Fragile Papers
  Box 50: Restricted fragile material. Reference surrogates have been substituted in the main files. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
  - Box 40, folders 876-877 (Box 50, Folder 970)
  - Box 42, folders 891-903 (Box 50, Folder 971-978)
  - Box 42, folders 904-910 (Box 50, Folder 979)
  - Box 43, folders 912-918 (Box 50, Folder 980)
- Restricted Fragile Oversize Papers
  Box 51: Restricted fragile material. Reference surrogates have been substituted in the main files. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
  - Box 11, folders 359-362 (Box 51, Folder 981)
  - Box 28, folder 635 (Box 51, Folder 982)
  - Box 42, folders 891-903 (Box 51, Folder 983-988)
  - Box 42, folders 904-910 (Box 51, Folder 989)
  - Box 43, folders 912-918 (Box 51, Folder 990)